Guide to the Alfred Schütz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files and Correspondence, 1927-1979; Series III; 6; (14 boxes)
  - Ferand, Ernest
    - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 24, Folder 530)
  - Fink, Eugen
    - Correspondence (photocopies), 1932-34 (Box 24, Folder 531)
  - Finkelstein, Louis
    - Correspondence, 1954-58 (Box 24, Folder 532)
  - Ford Foundation - Fund for the Advancement of Education
    - Correspondence, memos and printed material concerning grant application, 1957-58 (Box 25, Folder 533)
  - Foundation for Economic Education
    - Correspondence, 1948 Mar (Box 25, Folder 534)
  - France - Embassy
    - Correspondence, 1958 Nov 14 (Box 25, Folder 535)
  - Fredericson, Emil
    - Correspondence, 1949 Dec 10 (Box 25, Folder 536)
  - The Free Press
    - Correspondence, 1954-58 (Box 25, Folder 537)
  - Freeman, Beate
    - Correspondence, 1954 Jan (Box 25, Folder 538)
  - Friedmann, Marcel
    - Correspondence, 1939 Dec 1 (Box 25, Folder 539)
  - Froehlich, Walter
    - Correspondence, 1940-59 (Box 25, Folder 540)
  - Froeschels, Emil
    - Correspondence, 1949 May 27 (Box 25, Folder 541)
  - Frumkin, R. M.
    - Correspondence, 1959 Jul 25 (Box 25, Folder 542)
  - Furth, Herbert
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 543)
  - Garfinkel, Harold
    - Correspondence, 1949-58 (Box 25, Folder 544)
    - Mimeographs of papers: "Notes on the Sociological Attitude," "Notes Regarding some Research on the 'Problem' of Rationality," "Predicting the Effects of Time and Rate of Supervisory Succession Upon Group Performance," and "A Comparison of Decisions Made on Four Pre-Theoretical Parsons and Alfred Schütz.", 1953 (Box 25, Folder 545)
  - Glaser, William A.
    - Correspondence, 1956 Jan 20 (Box 25, Folder 546)
  - Glynn, Edmund S.
    - Correspondence, 1955 Nov 22 (Box 25, Folder 547)
  - Goddard, Arthur
    - Correspondence, 1946, 1955 (Box 25, Folder 548)
  - Goldman, Arthur[?]
    - "Some Apposite Remarks of Santayana and My Own Regarding a Few Points Raised in the Review of Parson's Structure of Social Action," typescript (Box 25, Folder 549)
  - Goldstein, Kurt
    - Correspondence, 1949-58 (Box 25, Folder 550)
  - Goldstein, Leon
    - Correspondence, 1954-58 (Box 25, Folder 551)
  - Gourevitch, Victor
    - Correspondence, 1949 Feb 22 (Box 25, Folder 552)
  - Grab, Herman de
    - Clipping - obituary, 1947 Mar 8 (Box 25, Folder 553)
  - Grunebaum, L. H.
    - Correspondence, 1956 Nov 29 (Box 25, Folder 554)
  - Gurwitsch, Alice
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1942 Apr 22 (Box 25, Folder 554a)
  - Gurwitsch, Aron
    See also: Series I, Studien zu Talcott Parsons, Box 1, folder 7
    - Correspondence, 1939-59, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 555-562)
    - Photocopies of letters from Gurwitsch to Schütz - originals not found, 1941, 1951 (Box 26, Folder 563)
    - Photocopies and typescript of letters from Schütz to Gurwitsch - provenance of originals not known, 1941-59 (Box 26, Folder 564)
    - Notes by Richard Grathoff on Schütz-Gurwitsch correspondence (Box 26, Folder 565)
    - Letter to Hans Staudinger, 19[59?] Jul 16 (Box 26, Folder 566)
    - Letter to Eric Voegelin, 1952 Nov 2 (Box 26, Folder 567)
    - Fullbright Award memo with statement of proposed activity by Gurwitsch and letter of recommendation by Alfred Schütz, [1957-58] (Box 26, Folder 568)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship - application and letter of recommendation by Alfred Schütz, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 569)
    - Note of recommendation for Joseph Olman [by Alfred Schütz?] (Box 26, Folder 570)
    - Announcement of lecture on "La conception de la conscience chez Kant et chez Husserl", 1959 Apr 25 (Box 26, Folder 571)
    - Essay: "Beitrag zur Phänomenologischen Theorie der Wahrnehmung," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 572)
    - Essay: "Der Bewusstseinsbegriff bei Kant und Husserl," typescript carbon (Box 26, Folder 573)
    - Essay: "Gelb-Goldstein's Concept of Concrete and the Phenomenology of Ideation," typescript carbon (Box 26, Folder 574)
    - Essay: "The Last Work of Edmund Husserl," typescript, corrected (Box 26, Folder 575)
    - Essay: "On the Intentionality of Consciousness," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 576)
    - Essay: "The Phenomenological and the Psychological Approach to Consciousness," typesript, carbon (Box 26, Folder 577)
    - Essay: "Présuppositions philosophiques de la logique," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 578)
    - Essay: "The Problem of Existence in Constitutive Phenomenology," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 579)
    - Essay: "Sur la conscience conceptuelle," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 580)
    - Essay: "Sur une racine perceptive de l'abstraction," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 581)
    - Essay: "Théorie du champ de la conscience," typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 26, Folder 582)
    - Essay: "Williams James' Notion of the Object of Thought," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 583)
    - Review of Edmund Husserl's Nachwort zu meinen "Ideen zu einer reinen Phänomenologie un phänomenologischen Philosophie", offprint, Deutsche Literaturzeitung, 1932 Feb 28 (Box 26, Folder 584)
    - Review of Jean-Paul Sartre's Transcendance of the Ego, typescript carbon, corrected, 1936-37 (Box 26, Folder 585)
  - H., Sylvia
    - Correspondence, 1957 Aug 21 (Box 26, Folder 586)
  - Haberler, Gottfried
    - Correspondence, 1940-58 (Box 26, Folder 587)
  - Hamburger, Ernest
    - Correspondence, 1942 Mar (Box 26, Folder 588)
  - Harvard College Library
    - Correspondence, 1958 Oct (Box 26, Folder 589)
  - Hayek, F. A.
    - Correspondence, 1936-58 (Box 26, Folder 590-590a)
    - Clipping, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 591)
  - Heimann, Edward
    - Correspondence, 1943 Feb 18 (Box 26, Folder 592)
  - Hendel, Charles
    - Correspondence, 1941 Jan 2 (Box 26, Folder 593)
  - Henle, Mary
    - Correspondence, 1953, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 594)
  - Hering, Jean
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 595)
  - Hill, Reuben
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 596)
  - Hirsch, Herr und Frau
    - Draft of letter by Alfred Schütz, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 597)
  - Hirschfeld, Gerhard
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 26, Folder 598)
  - Hook, Sidney
    - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 26, Folder 599)
  - Horecki, Robert
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 600)
  - Horne, Herman
    - Correspondence, 1941 Aug 4 (Box 26, Folder 601)
  - Horowitz, Irving Lewis
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 26, Folder 602)
  - Hosiosky, I.
    - Correspondence, 1958 Dec 2 (Box 26, Folder 603)
  - Hovde, Bryn J.
    - Correspondence, 1947 May 26 (Box 26, Folder 604)
  - Hula, Erich
    - Correspondence, 1944-49 (Box 27, Folder 605)
  - Hunna, Lilo
    - Correspondence, 1956 Oct 25 (Box 27, Folder 606)
  - Hunold, A.
    - Correspondence, 1954 Nov 22 (Box 27, Folder 607)
  - Husserl, Edmund
    - Transcripts of letter to Schütz, 1932 May 3 (Box 27, Folder 608)
  - Husserl, Gerhard
    - Correspondence, 1939-40 (Box 27, Folder 609)
  - Husserl, Malvine
    - Correspondence, 1938-39 (Box 27, Folder 610)
      Includes obituary announcement, 1950
  - Husserl family
    - Postcard signed Edmund, Malvine and others, 1936 Nov 9 (Box 27, Folder 611)
  - Husserl[?]
    - Note with addresses, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 612)
  - Huth, Anna
    - Correspondence, 1956 Nov 5 (Box 27, Folder 613)
  - Hyppolite, Jean
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 27, Folder 614)
  - Ihrig, Howard
    - Correspondence, 1948 Dec 12 (Box 27, Folder 615)
  - Ingarden, Roman
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 27, Folder 616)
  - Internationale Stiftung Mozarteum
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 617)
  - International Phenomenological Society
    - Accounting reports, 1942, 1946 (Box 27, Folder 618)
    - Correspondence and announcements, 1940-56 (Box 27, Folder 619)
    - Constitution and notes (Box 27, Folder 620)
  - Jamieson, K. I.
    - Correspondence, 1960 Feb 29 (Box 27, Folder 621)
  - Johnson, Alvin
    - Correspondence, 1940-58 (Box 27, Folder 622)
    - Letters to Ilse Schütz, 1959-69 (Box 27, Folder 623)
    - Clipping and announcements, 1949-69 (Box 27, Folder 624)
  - Jonas, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1954-60 (Box 27, Folder 625)
  - Journal of Philosophy
    - Correspondence, 1950, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 626)
  - Kahn, Erich Itor
    - Correspondence, 1941-45 (Box 27, Folder 627)
      Includes photographic print
  - Kallen, Horace M.
    - Correspondence, 1940-56 (Box 27, Folder 628)
  - Kaplan, Bernard
    - Correspondence, 1956, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 629)
  - Kaufmann, Else
    See also: Series I, In Memory of Felix Kaufmann, Box 11, folder 190
    - Correspondence, 1950-53 (Box 27, Folder 630)
  - Kaufmann, Felix
    See also: Series I, Einleitung zur Bearbeitung der Husserl-Manuskripte, Box 14, folder 259
    - Correspondence, 1938-48 (Box 27, Folder 631)
    - "Ausgewählte Miseskreislieder," mimeograph, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 632)
    - "The Pursuit of Clarity," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 633)
    - Clipping, 1949 Dec (Box 27, Folder 634)
  - Kaufmann, Fritz
    - Correspondence, 1958 May 29 (Box 27, Folder 635)
      Includes obituary notice
    - Letter to Marvin Farber, 1943 Apr 22 (Box 27, Folder 636)
  - Kelson, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1942-45 (Box 27, Folder 637)
  - Kemperdinck, Gustav
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 27, Folder 638)
  - Kennington, Richard H.
    - Correspondence, 1959 Mar 24 (Box 27, Folder 639)
  - Kenyon Review
    - Correspondence, 1954 Jan 30 (Box 27, Folder 640)
  - Kirchheimer, Otto
    - Correspondence, 1957 May 22 (Box 27, Folder 641)
  - K. F. Koehler Verlag
    - Correspondence, 1958 Jan 16 (Box 27, Folder 642)
  - Koehler, Wolfgang
    - Correspondence, 1940 Dec 31 (Box 27, Folder 643)
  - Kracauer, Siegfried
    - Correspondence, 1946, 1951 (Box 27, Folder 644)
  - Kris, Ernst
    - Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 645)
  - Krushaar, Otto
    - Correspondence, 1940-41 (Box 27, Folder 646)
  - Kuffner, Stephan
    - Correspondence, 1947 Aug 19 (Box 27, Folder 647)
  - Kuhn, Helmut
    - Correspondence, 1942-58 (Box 27, Folder 648)
  - Kuhn, Kaethe
    - Letters to Ilse Schütz, 1944 (Box 27, Folder 649)
  - Kullmann, Eugene
    - Correspondence, 1954, 1958, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 650)
  - Kuypers, K.
    - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 27, Folder 651)
  - Lachmann, L. M.
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 652)
  - Lameere, Jean
    - Correspondence, 1949 Feb (Box 27, Folder 653)
  - Landau, Martin
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 654)
  - Landowska
    - Clipping of portrait, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 655)
  - Langer, Susanne K.
    - Correspondence, 1959 Mar 10 (Box 27, Folder 656)
  - Lauer, Quentin
    - Correspondence, 1957 Jan 19 (Box 27, Folder 657)
  - Lean Martin
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 27, Folder 658)
  - Lebeaux, Lillian
    - Correspondence, 1945 Jun 14 (Box 27, Folder 659)
  - Leent, J. A. A. van
    - Correspondence, 1957 Apr 22 (Box 27, Folder 660)
  - Leitner, Franz H.
    - Correspondence, 1952 Jul 21 (Box 27, Folder 661)
  - Liebowitz, Bernard
    - Correspondence, 1959 May 6 (Box 27, Folder 662)
  - Lincoln, Harry B.
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 663)
  - Lowe, Adolph
    - Correspondence, 1942-58 (Box 27, Folder 664-666)
  - Löwith, Karl
    - Correspondence, 1952-53 (Box 27, Folder 667)
  - Luckman, Thomas
    - Correspondence, 1958, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 668)
  - McGill, V. J. (Jerry)
    - Correspondence, 1942-55 (Box 28, Folder 669)
  - McKinney, John C.
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 670)
  - McKeon, Richard P.
    - Correspondence, 1952 Sep 11 (Box 28, Folder 671)
  - Machlup, Fritz
    - Correspondence, 1934-58, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 672-681)
    - Letter to Amherst College, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 682)
    - Letter to F. A. Hayek, 1944 Jan 4 (Box 28, Folder 683)
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1959 Jun 1 (Box 28, Folder 684)
    - Letter to United States. Internal Revenue Service, [1954?] (Box 28, Folder 685)
    - Letter to United States. State Department, 1943 Aug 31 (Box 28, Folder 686)
    - Letter of Introduction for Alfred Schütz to Prof. Knight, Univ. of Buffalo, 1940 Dec (Box 28, Folder 687)
    - Letter from unknown, 1938 Jul 9 (Box 28, Folder 688)
    - "Rejoinder to a Reluctant Ultra-Empiricist," typescript carbon, corrected (Box 28, Folder 689)
    - Researchers' notes on Schütz-Machlup letters, 1976 Sep (Box 28, Folder 690)
  - Machlup, Hanna
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 691)
  - Machup, Stefan
    - Correspondence, 1943-55 (Box 28, Folder 692)
  - MacIver, Robert M.
    - Correspondence, 1953-57 (Box 28, Folder 693)
  - Main, Alvin N.
    - Correspondence, 1956 Oct 12 (Box 28, Folder 694)
  - Mandelbaum, Maurice
    - Correspondence, 1940-57, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 695)
  - Maritain, Jacques
    - Correspondence, 1940-42 (Box 28, Folder 696)
  - Marx, Werner
    - Correspondence, 1952-59 (Box 28, Folder 697)
  - Mayer, Carl
    - Correspondence, 1945-54 (Box 28, Folder 698)
  - Merleau-Ponty, Maurice
    - Correspondence, 1955-57 (Box 28, Folder 699)
  - Merton, Robert K.
    - Correspondence, 1940 Jan 20 (Box 28, Folder 700)
  - Merlan, Philip
    - Correspondence, 1941-57 (Box 28, Folder 701)
  - Mintz, Maximilian
    - Correspondence, 1941-42 (Box 28, Folder 702)
  - Moeller, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 28, Folder 703)
  - Mont Pelerin Society
    - Letters and reports, 1953-58 (Box 28, Folder 704)
      See also: Hayek, F. A., Box 26, folders 590-590a
  - Moore, Wilbert
    - Correspondence, 1952 Mar 21 (Box 28, Folder 705)
  - Mora, Ferrater
    - Correspondence, 1958 May 15 (Box 28, Folder 706)
  - Morgenbesser, Sidney
    - Correspondence (Box 28, Folder 707)
  - Morgenstern, Oskar
    - Correspondence, 1952, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 708)
  - Munitz, Prof. [Milton?]
    - Correspondence, 1950 Apr 15 (Box 28, Folder 709)
  - Murray, John Courtney
    - Correspondence, 1956 Jun 25 (Box 28, Folder 710)
  - Naegele, Kaspar
    - Correspondence, 1954[?], 1956 (Box 28, Folder 711)
  - Natanson, Charlie
    - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 28, Folder 712)
  - Natanson, Lois
    - Correspondence, 1955, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 713)
  - Natanson, Maurice
    - Correspondence, 1951-59, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 714-720)
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1959 May 17 (Box 29, Folder 721)
    - Correspondence regarding Natanson's applications for fellowships and jobs - with letters of recommendation from Alfred Schütz, 1951-57 (Box 29, Folder 722)
    - "Finding a Fulcrum for Reason's Lever," review of Herman Dooyeweerd's A New Critique of Theoretical Thought, printed version, The Christian Century, 1954 Jun 2 (Box 29, Folder 723)
    - "Philosophy and the Social Sciences," mimeograph, 1952[?] (Box 29, Folder 724)
    - [Review of Mikel Dufrenne's Phénoménologie de l"experience Esthétique, offprint, 1954 Sep (Box 29, Folder 725)
    - Clipping and photograph prints of children (Box 29, Folder 726)
  - Nédoncelle, Maurice
    - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 29, Folder 727)
  - Neisser, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1956-58 (Box 29, Folder 728)
  - Nettler, Gwynne
    - Correspondence, 1944 Jun 7 (Box 29, Folder 729)
  - Neurath, Paul
    - Correspondence (Box 29, Folder 730)
  - New School for Social Research
    - Alumni Association correspondence, 1952, 1955 (Box 29, Folder 731)
    - Appointment and career letters for Alfred Schütz, 1942-58 (Box 29, Folder 732)
    - Bulletins, 1951 (Box 29, Folder 733)
    - Clipping, 1956 Feb 12 (Box 29, Folder 734)
    - Commencement Program, 1953 Jun 2 (Box 29, Folder 735)
    - Graduate faculty correspondence and reports, 1945-58 (Box 29, Folder 736)
    - Graduate faculty memos
      - by Alfred Schütz: untitled to Hans Staudinger, mimeograph, 1956 Feb 23 (Box 29, Folder 737)
      - by Alfred Schütz: untitled - proposal for set of books on the social sciences for German audiences, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 738)
      - by Alfred Schütz: "The Scope and Function of a Department of Philosophy within the graduate faculty," drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected, with mimeograph (includes photocopy of draft accompanied by letter from Lester Embree to Ilse Schütz, 1985 May 26), 1953 (Box 29, Folder 739)
      - By others, 1956, 1958, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 740)
    - Material on the revision of the MA program, with a prospectus for Victor Bunagin, 1952 (Box 29, Folder 741)
  - New York University. Graduate School of Business Administration Alumni Association
    - Correspondence, 1948 Mar 30 (Box 29, Folder 742)
  - Nicol, Eduardo
    - Correspondence, 1955, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 743)
  - Osborn, Andrew
    - Correspondence, 1958 Oct 16 (Box 29, Folder 744)
  - Otaka, Tomoo
    - Correspondence, 1932, 1953 (Box 29, Folder 745)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 746)
  - Padover, Saul K.
    - Correspondence, 1959 May 6 (Box 29, Folder 747)
  - Parsons, Talcott
    - Draft of letter from Alfred Schütz with note from Parsons, 1939, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 748)
    - "Socialization of the Child as a Sociological Problem," typescript, 1953 Apr 30 (Box 29, Folder 749)
  - Peabody Conservatory
    - Correspondence, 1956-57 (Box 29, Folder 750)
  - Peursen, Cornelis Anthonie van
    - Correspondence, 1956[?] Aug 7 (Box 29, Folder 751)
  - Pekelis, Alexander
    - Correspondence, 1945 Apr 19 (Box 29, Folder 752)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton
    - Correspondence, 1941 Mar 25 (Box 29, Folder 753)
  - Pettee, George S.
    - Correspondence, 1955 Oct 17 (Box 29, Folder 754)
  - Philosophical Abstracts
    - Correspondence, 1943 Dec 20 (Box 29, Folder 755)
  - The Philosophic Mind
    - Issues, 1939-40 (Box 30, Folder 756)
  - Philosophische Rundschau
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 757)
  - Philosophy and Phenomenological Research
    - Correspondence, 1959 May 16 (Box 30, Folder 758)
  - Pleydell-Pearce, A. W.
    - Correspondence, 1957 Jul 17 (Box 30, Folder 759)
  - Popper, Karl
    - Correspondence, 1950, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 760)
  - Princeton University
    - Correspondence, 1951-54 (Box 30, Folder 761)
      Includes copy of "Decision-making as an Approach to the Study of International Politics" by Richard Snyder, et al.
    - Office of Public Opinion Research - Correspondence, 1943 Feb 12 (Box 30, Folder 762)
  - Princeton University Press
    - Correspondence, 1957-58 (Box 30, Folder 763)
  - Progoff, Ira
    - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 764)
  - Rabinerson, Raoul
    - Correspondence, 1939 Dec 15 (Box 30, Folder 765)
  - Recasens Siches, Luis
    - Correspondence, 1942-58 (Box 30, Folder 766)
  - The Review of Metaphysics
    - Correspondence, 1955-58 (Box 30, Folder 766a)
  - Riezler, Kurt
    - Correspondence, 1955, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 767)
  - Roberts, Gertrude
    - Correspondence, 1947 Aug 27 (Box 30, Folder 768)
  - Rock, Irvin
    - Correspondence, 1951 Oct 23 (Box 30, Folder 769)
  - Ronall, Joachim O.
    - Correspondence, 1958 Jun 10 (Box 30, Folder 770)
  - Rosenberg, Bernard
    - Correspondence, 1958 Nov 11 (Box 30, Folder 771)
  - Rosenberg, Elizabeth Husserl
    - Correspondence, 1941, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 772)
  - Rosenstein-Rodan, Paul N.
    - Correspondence, 1948 Feb 16 (Box 30, Folder 773)
  - Roucek, Joseph S.
    - Correspondence, 1944 Jun 12 (Box 30, Folder 774)
  - Rougier, Louis
    - Correspondence, 1945-55 (Box 30, Folder 775)
  - Rueff, Jacques
    - Correspondence, 1957 Mar 26 (Box 30, Folder 776)
  - Salomon, Albert
    See also: Series I, Memoranda on the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research, Box 14, folder 254
    - Correspondence, 1942-59 (Box 30, Folder 777)
    - Outlines for courses and books (Box 30, Folder 778)
    - Clipping - obituary, 1966 Dec 10 (Box 30, Folder 779)
  - Schapiro, Meyer
    - Correspondence, 1940-56 (Box 30, Folder 780)
  - Schermann, Hans
    - Correspondence with Ilse Schütz, 1964-65 (Box 30, Folder 781)
  - Schütz, Evelyn
    - Clipping, 1953 Jul 22 (Box 30, Folder 782)
  - Shibutani, T.
    - Correspondence, 1955 Jun 24 (Box 30, Folder 783)
  - Schiff, Erich
    - Correspondence, 1941, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 784)
  - Schumann, Elizabeth
    - Correspondence, 1942 May 17 (Box 30, Folder 785)
  - Schueller, Richard
    - Correspondence, 1948, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 786)
  - Seeman, Melvin
    - Correspondence, 1958 Dec 15 (Box 30, Folder 787)
  - Shils, Edward
    - Correspondence, 1954, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 788)
  - Silverman, Leslie
    - Correspondence, 1951 Jun 4 (Box 30, Folder 789)
  - Simon, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1952-59 (Box 30, Folder 790)
    - Clipping, 1955 May 15 (Box 30, Folder 791)
  - Sjoberg, G.
    - Correspondence, 1953 Oct 19 (Box 30, Folder 792)
  - Social Research
    See also: Series I, Wilhelm Meisters Wanderjahren, Box 2, folders 28-30
    - Correspondence, 1944-56, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 793)
    - Editorial Board meeting agendae, 1954-56 (Box 30, Folder 794)
  - Sonnemann, Ulrich
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 795)
  - Spiegelberg, Herbert
    - Correspondence, 1940-59, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 796)
    - Letter to Marvin Farber, 1951 Nov 4 (Box 30, Folder 797)
  - Stadler, Victor
    - Correspondence, 1940, 1942 (Box 30, Folder 798)
    - Clipping - obituary, 1946 Jun (Box 30, Folder 799)
  - Stark, W.
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 30, Folder 800)
  - Staudinger, Else
    - Correspondence, 1947, 1955, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 801)
  - Staudinger, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1940-59, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 802)
    - Letter to Ilse Schütz, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 803)
    - Letter to Henry David, 1959 May 22 (Box 30, Folder 804)
  - Stechert-Hafner, Inc.
    - Correspondence, 1958 Oct 14 (Box 30, Folder 805)
  - Stein, Edith
    - Clippings, 1952, 1979, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 806)
  - Stein, Maurice
    - Correspondence, 1957 Sep 16 (Box 30, Folder 807)
  - Stein, Waltraut
    - Correspondence, 1958-59 (Box 30, Folder 808)
  - Stern, Alfred
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 809)
  - Stewart, Reginald
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 30, Folder 810)
  - Stillman, Michael
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 30, Folder 811)
  - Strasser, Stefan
    - Correspondence, 1955-58 (Box 30, Folder 812)
  - Strauss, Leo
    - Correspondence, 1943-58 (Box 30, Folder 813)
  - Sulzbach[?], W.
    - Correspondence, 1940 Nov 30 (Box 30, Folder 814)
  - Taubes, Jacob
    - Correspondence, 1955, 1957, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 815)
  - Tipografica Editora Argentina
    - Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 816)
  - 12th Street: A Quarterly
    - Correspondence, 1950 Apr 14 (Box 30, Folder 817)
  - Tyhurst, J. S.
    - Correspondence, 1949 Jun 23 (Box 30, Folder 818)
  - Udin, S.
    - Correspondence, 1956 May 27 (Box 30, Folder 819)
  - United States. Office of Economic Warfare
    - Correspondence, 1943-47 (Box 31, Folder 820)
    - Civil Service Application, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 821)
    - Résumés, 1943 (Box 31, Folder 822)
    - Personal and Financial Affidavits for Alfred Schütz, 1939-43 (Box 31, Folder 823)
    - Report by Alfred Schütz: "Agricultural Credit in Germany," typescript carbon, 1943 Sep (Box 31, Folder 824)
  - United States. War Manpower Commission
    - National Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel - information form submitted by Alfred Schütz, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 825)
  - Unity of Science Congress
    - Correspondence, 1939 Aug 25 (Box 31, Folder 826)
  - University of Chicago Press
    - Correspondence, 1944, 1958 (Box 31, Folder 827)
  - Vanden Waal, Hans
    - Correspondence, 1948, 1957 (Box 31, Folder 828)
  - Voegelin, Eric
    - Correspondence, 1940-59, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 829-849)
    - Letter to Aron Gurwitsch, 1957 Jun 17 (Box 31, Folder 850)
    - List of Schütz-Voegelin letters made by Helmut Wagner, 1983 Aug 10 (Box 31, Folder 851)
    - Statement about Voegelin for Guggenheim Fellowship [by Alfred Schütz?], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 852)
    - "Der autoritäre Staatsfern," printed version, Wiener Zeitung, 1934 Apr 27